Masoud Asadzadeh

C# .NET Backend Developer

Switzerland, Lugano (Swiss B Permit with work permit, open for relocation)
 ■ masoud.asadzade@gmail.com
 +41779666625
 linkedin

Language: English



WORK EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer (2019 (remote)) ♥ Hamfekran IT Group Project: E-Government, User Monitoring, and Ticketing

- Contributed to the development of REST APIs on microservice architecture
 with the focus on connecting the internal government system to on-line interfaces and allowing citizens to transact with government entities to renew
 their licenses, to pay tax/fines/car tolls/property tolls, and to communicate
 with police entities.
- Created backend for single page event log analyzer and ticketing application.

Backend Developer (2018-2019 (remote)) ♥ Hamfekran IT Group Project: AutoTaxi (ETAXI)

- Designed and developed workflows and processes for taxi-business to serve taxi companies' needs of metropolitan cities such as buying/selling taxies, issuing driving certificates, school services.
- Participated in the design and development of microservice architecture to meet the process-oriented business needs.
- Achieved improvement in the system's speed by 50% and enhanced scalability and maintainability.

Backend Developer (2016–2017) ♥ Hamfekran IT Group Project: E-Commerce Application (Epardis)

- Designed and developed backend and database for NopCommerce (open source E-commerce) for booking services such as catering, equipment hire, and car rental.
- Unified the process of document generation and transmission engine by building a set of libraries and interfaces (E-Letters).

Backend Developer (2014–2017) ♥ Hamfekran IT Group Project: Automation of Vehicle Technical Inspection (VTI)

- Automated the recognition and image processing of vehicles' number plates.
- Assisted to record inspection hardware outputs & to issue the certification.
- Established a fully customizable inspection software for users across the country.

Developer (2013–2016) ♥ Hamfekran IT Group

Project: Funeral Service Management

- When I was hired, the FSM Application was scattered into decentralized apps which had massive cost on support, development, and maintenance.
- Achieved, roughly, a 200% improvement in performance by developing a centralized webApp supporting selling accessories, GIS mapping capabilities, custom reports as well as integrating with BI programs.

End to End Developer (2013 -2014)

♀ Contract

Project: Supply Chain Automation - Carpet, Textile, Home Furnishing

- Developed core functionalities of SCM operations for the management of customer orders, sourcing, planning, logistics, warehouse, and payroll, financial operations, inventory, distribution, import-export, etc.
- Exported invoices to MS excel and Crystal reporting service to save time and money by removing paper works.

ABOUT

A software developer with a demonstrated history in the industry who worked on commercial countrywide and corporate IT-type applications, developing and maintaining newly developed and legacy progressive apps utilizing ORD and .NET in a scrum team. Willing to learn who can play a reliable and loyal role in a team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages	
C#	••••
C++	••••
TSQL	••••
HTML, JavaScript, CSS	••••
Web Frameworks ASP.NET Web Forms ASP.NET MVC	••••
Desktop Frameworks	
Windows Forms	••••
WPF	••••
Communication Frameworks	
ASP.NET WebAPI, WCF	••••
ASMX web Service	••••
ORM	
Entity Framework	••••
ADO.NET, LINQ	••••
DataBases	
MS SQL Server	••••
Reporting	
MS SQL Reporting Service	••••
Crystal Reports	••••
Versioning and Build Tools TFS, MicrosoftVisualStudio	••••
3rd Party .NET	
DNN (CMS)	••••
NopCommerce (E-commerce)	••••
Server Technologies	
Windows Server, IIS	••••
SDLC	
Agile development/Scrum	••••

Solid principle, DesignPattern

FREELANCING PROJECTS

Legacy Migration on Real Estate Portfolio Management

Contributed to the migration of MS Access database to SQL Server and Web Form app into MVC.

Automation System of Transportation

Developed a distributed desktop solution that offers transportation services throughout the country. All orders are logged from the registration time to delivery time using RFID tech.

Flight Information Display App

Created an application to display real-time flight information for passengers can be used in airports and hotels. It can be connected to online flight information data source and customizable to show Ads.

WCF Service front-ended by USSD

Developed a service to issue up to 15-thousands real-time permits a day to control the entrance of vehicle's into traffic zones.

Payment Provider

Worked with POS terminals SDK for developing payment providers.

Facial Navigator Speaker

Implemented a voice-face recognition prototype for navigation purpose using EmguCV (.NET wrapper for C++ OpenCV computer vision library). Composed of six components: Face Detector, face database, Training Set Manager, Face Recognizer, speaker, Speech Recognizer.

EDUCATION

B.Sc in Software Engineering University of Science and Culture (2005–2010) ♥ Tehran, Iran

Diploma in Mathematics School of Exceptional Talents (NODET) (2002-2005)♥ Bojnord, Iran

TEACHING ASSISTANT

Advanced Programming C++, Mathematics

PUBLICATION

Forecasting rail transport petroleum consumption using an integrated model of autocorrelation functions-artificial neural network. Journal of Acta Polytechnica Hungarica, 11(2), 203-214.

SOFT SKILS

Cooperative, adaptable, enthusiastic about learning, and reliable.

HOBBIES

Watching Documentaries

■ Reading ♣ Hiking